A Guide to the St. Mark's Episcopal Church Records, 1866-2016
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
St. Mark's Episcopal Church Records, 1866-2016
The Library of Virginia
41476
77.67 cu. ft.
St. Mark's Episcopal Church
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of St. Mark's Episcopal Church, 2004 September (Acc. 41476).
Gift of H. Harwood Dunston, 2008 February (Acc. 43680). [6 photographs of Rev. Warnecke added to collection]
Historical Information
In 1860 Dr. Joshua Peterkin, Rector of St. James's Episcopal Church felt there was need for an additional Episcopal Church in Richmond. He persuaded some members of his own church to help form the new church. A subscription list was started and $5,000 in pledges was collected. With these pledges a lot was purchased on Clay Street. However, these early steps toward formation were halted by the outbreak of the Civil War. After the war, despite the death of many of the subscribers and the poor financial outlook of those who remained, an attempt was made to continue with the formation of the new church. A much needed boost came when an agreement with the Society of Friends was reached by which the lot purchased in 1860 was switched with that of a lot owned by the Society, at the corner of Leigh and Foushee. The Society of Friends also paid an additional $1600 to St. Mark's as part of the arrangement. With these funds a small church was constructed. On 25 March 1866 the first services were held under the direction of St. Mark's first rector, Thomas Grayson Dashiel. In 1868 St. Mark's was offered a vacant property between Clay and Leigh, by the Executive Committee of the Diocesan Missionary Society, which once housed a mission church. In 1871 the church again moved locations, when it relocated to the corner of Clay and First Streets. A new building was constructed using some materials from the Clay and Leigh property. In 1919 the location of St. Mark's Church again began to be discussed. The idea of a merger with two other local churches, Grace Church and Holy Trinity Church were debated, but these plans were voted down. In the same year it was decided that the church should move to the west of the city and under the direction of its new rector, Dr. William Smith, the existing church was sold and a new site was purchased on Boulevard. In 1922, after holding services in the Robert E. Lee School, the Church held its first services in the parish hall of its new building at 520 North Boulevard, where it still holds services today.
Scope and Content
Records, 1866-2016, of St. Mark's Episcopal Church, Richmond, Virginia, including annual meeting reports, audio-visual material, bulletins, clippings, committee files, correspondence, diocesan materials, minutes, newsletters, photographs, registers (baptismal, burial, marriage and membership), and reports related to various aspects of the church. Items of interest include various newsletters produced by the church, including "The Beacon," "The Caller," "The Lion's Tale," and "St. Mark's Beacon."
Also of note are the files of two organizations within the church: The Vestry and the Women's group. The Vestry acted as the governing body making decisions about the church and its finances and the Women's group did much fundraising and outreach for the church. The Vestry files include minutes of meetings, correspondence, treasurer reports, as well as other business related materials. The Women's group of the church was known by several titles, including the Women's Auxiliary, the Women of St. Mark's, and finally the Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's. Their records detail, through correspondence, minutes and treasurer's reports, their volunteer work, fundraising and outreach activities.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- "A Carol for Candlemas," by Edward Meeks Gregory and Vernon Perdue-Davis, not dated. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1942-1948. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Annual Meeting, 1949-1955. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Annual Meeting, 1957-1968. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Annual Meeting, 1969-1972. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Annual Meeting, 1973. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Annual Meeting, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Annual Meeting, 1975. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Annual Meeting, 1976. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Annual Meeting, 1977. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Annual Meeting, 1978. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Annual Meeting, 1977. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Annual Meeting, 1978. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Annual Meeting, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Annual Meeting, 1980. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Annual Meeting, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Annual Meeting, 1983. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Annual Meeting, 1984. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Annual Reports from Committees, 1975-1976. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- The Beacon, 1937-1938. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- The Bible (LP, Vinyl), 1943. (Box 53)
- Bishop Kivengere Mission, 1980-1981. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Boy Scouts Troop 724, 1955-1970. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Brief Historical Sketch of St. Mark's Church, not dated. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Brief History of St. Mark's, 1941. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Brown, Robert L. -- Certificate as Patron of Smithsonian Institution (oversized), not dated. (Box 48)
- Building and Equipment Committee, 1980-1987. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Bulletins, 1949-1959. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Bulletins, 1971. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Bulletins, 1972. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Bulletins, 1974. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Bulletins, 1976. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Bulletins, 1977. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Bulletins, 1978. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Bulletins, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Bulletins, 1980. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Bulletins, 1981. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Bulletins, 1982. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Bulletins, January-June 1986. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Bulletins, July-December 1986. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Bulletins, 1987. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Bulletins, 1988. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Bulletins, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Bulletins, 1991. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Bulletins, 1992. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Bulletins, 1993. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Bulletins, 1994. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Bulletins, January-June 1995. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Bulletins, July-December 1995. (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Bulletins, January-April 1996. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Bulletins, May-August 1996. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Bulletins, September-December 1996. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Bulletins, January-May 1997. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Bulletins, June-August 1997. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Bulletins, September-December 1997-1998. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Buttrick, William -- Liturgical Desk Calendar, 1979. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- The Caller, 1959-1966. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- The Caller, 1970-1971. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- The Caller, 1972. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- The Caller, 1973-1974. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- The Caller, 1975-1976. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- The Caller, 1977-1980. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- The Caller, 1981-1983. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- The Caller,. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- The Caller, 1986. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- The Caller, 1987-1988. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- The Caller, 1990. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- The Caller, 1991. (Box 9, Folder 4)
- The Caller, 1992. (Box 9, Folder 5)
- The Caller, 1993. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- The Caller, 1994-1996. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Camp and Conferences, 1980. (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Campaign 2000, 2000. (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Candelabra -- Documents, 1970. (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Cash Sheets, 1933. (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Choir Register, 1898. (Box 49)
- Christian Education -- Church School, 1978-1979. (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Christian Education -- Church School, 1979. (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Christian Education -- Covenant Committee, 1973-1981. (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Christian Education -- General, 1976-1977. (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Christian Education -- Joint Jubilee, 1980. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Certificates, 1959-1988. (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Christian Education -- Vacation Church School, 1978. (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Christmas, 1978. (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Christmas, 1979-1980. (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Christmas Pageant, 1979. (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Christmas Pageant Material, 1951-1968. (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Church Signage, not dated. (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Church School, 1959-1971. (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Church School, 1963-1969. (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Church School, 1969-1974. (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Church School, 1973-1977. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Clippings, 1872-1954. (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Clippings, 1961-1991. (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Clippings, not dated. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Communications Committee, 1969-1970. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Confirmation, 1979. (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Confirmation, 1980. (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Consecration of St. Mark's, 1946. (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Construction Records, 1945-1948. (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Construction Records, 1948. (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Construction Records, 1949-1950. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Correspondence -- Bertha Ellett, 1949-1953. (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Correspondence -- Mrs. Howard Liesfeld, 1950. (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Correspondence -- Miscellaneous, 1977-1978. (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Correspondence -- Miscellaneous, 1980-1988. (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Correspondence -- Principles of Church Union, 1968. (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Correspondence -- Stained Class Window, 1929. (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Council of the Diocese, 1970-1971. (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Couples Club, 1977. (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Daughters of the King -- Flower Fund Ledger, 1914-1931. (Box 43)
- The Daughters of the King -- Hand Book, not dated. (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Daughters of the King -- Membership Register, 1919-1931. (Box 43)
- Daughters of the King -- Minute Book, 1906-1912. (Box 43)
- Daughters of the King -- Minute Book, 1912-1921. (Box 43)
- Dedication of Embroidered Kneeling Cushions, not dated. (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Dedication of Petronius S. Jones Park, 1988. (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Dismissal Service, 1958. (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Diocese of Virginia -- 180th Annual Council Meeting, 1975. (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Diocese of Virginia -- 183rd Annual Council Meeting, 1978-1980. (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Diocese of Virginia -- 184th Annual Council Meeting, 1978-1979. (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Diocese of Virginia -- Christianity in Action, 1947. (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Diocese of Virginia -- Division of the Diocese, 1979-1980. (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Diocese of Virginia -- Region X Council, 1972-1974. (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Diocese of Virginia, Region X Episcopal Churchwomen, 1977. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Diocese of Virginia, Region X Episcopal Churchwomen Presidents Meeting, 1976-1977. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Diocese of Virginia -- Report to the 157th Annual Council, 1952. (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Diocese of Virginia -- Special Council, 1979. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Directory, not dated. (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Directory, 1985. (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Directory, 1990. (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Directory, 1994. (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Early St. Mark's Recollections, 1984. (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Easter Service (Film, 16mm), not dated. (Box 53)
- Episcopal Church Women Diocese of Virginia Annual Meeting, 1976. (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Episcopal Churchwomen, Diocese of Virginia, Hand Book for Branch Officers and Chairmen, 1965. (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Episcopal Churchwomen, Diocese of Virginia -- Yearbook, 1964. (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Episcopal Churchwomen, Diocese of Virginia -- Yearbook, 1965-1966. (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Episcopal Churchwomen, Diocese of Virginia -- Yearbook, 1967-1968. (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Episcopal Churchwomen, Diocese of Virginia -- Year Book, 1968-1969. (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Episcopal Churchwomen, Diocese of Virginia -- Year Book, 1969-1970. (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Episcopal Churchwomen, Diocese of Virginia -- Year Book, 1970-1971. (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Episcopal Churchwomen, Diocese of Virginia -- Year Book, 1971-1972. (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Episcopal Churchwomen, Diocese of Virginia -- Year Book, 1974-1975. (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Agendas, 1974-1975. (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Agendas, 1975-1976. (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Agendas, 1976-1977. (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's, 1977-1978. (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Annual Branch Reports to Diocese, 1975-1979. (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Annual Reports, 1976-1978. (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Annual Report, 1988. (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Annual Report, 1990-1991. (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Annual Report, 1994. (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Annual Report of the President, 1978. (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Donations and Expenses, 1980-1982. (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Installation of Officers, not dated. (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Job Guidelines, 1979. (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Marks's -- Minutes, 1976-1978. (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Episcopal Church Women -- Study Materials, 1965-1973. (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Yearbook, 1988-1989. (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Yearbook, 1989-1990. (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Yearbook, 1990-1991. (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Yearbook, 1991-1992. (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Yearbook, 1992-1993. (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Yearbook, 1993-1994. (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Episcopal Church Women of St. Mark's -- Yearbook, 1996-1997. (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Every Member Canvass, 1946-1949. (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Every Member Canvass Material, 1949-1969. (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Every Member Canvass Material, 1949-1952. (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Every Member Canvass Material, 1954-1956. (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Every Member Canvass, 1970. (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Every Member Canvass, 1971. (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Every Member Canvass, 1972. (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Every Member Canvass, 1973. (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Every Member Canvass, 1974. (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Every Member Canvass, 1975. (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Every Member Canvass, 1976. (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Every Member Canvass 1978, 1974-1977. (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Every Member Canvass, 1979. (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Faure's Requiem Concert, 1995. (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Festival Holy Eucharist to Celebrate the Renovation of the Nave and Chancel of St. Mark's, 1997. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Folk Mass, 1968. (Box 16, Folder 8)
- General Convention, 1976. (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Gill, Charles, 1979-2004. (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Good Friday Concert Poster -- Faure's Requiem (oversized), 1995. (Box 48)
- Guest Book Pages, 1982-1987. (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Guild of the Christ Child, 1955-1960. (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Historical Summary, not dated. (Box 16, Folder 13)
- History of St. Mark's Episcopal Church, B.A. thesis by Matt J. Hudgins, University of Richmond, 1955. (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Hollywood Cemetery burial information for Mary T. W. Parker, 1932. (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Holy Matrimony -- Completed Weddings, 1979-1980. (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Hospitality Committee, 1977-1978. (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Housekeeping, 1972-1974. (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Inter faith Council, 1977-1978. (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Invitation (Video Beta), not dated. (Box 53)
- Invitation to Last Service at Clay and First Streets, 1919. (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Johnston-Willis Hospital, 1954-1962. (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Johnston-Willis Hospital, 1967-1980. (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Laying of the Corner Stone of St. Mark's, 1921. (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Lent, 1977. (Box 16, Folder 24)
- Lenten Calendar, 1960. (Box 16, Folder 25)
- Lenten Program -- Joint Services, 1955-1961. (Box 16, Folder 26)
- Lenten Program, 1978. (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Lenten Program, 1979. (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Lenten Services, 1888. (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Lenten Services Pamphlet, 1951. (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Lenten Study Course, 1980. (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Letters and Notes on North Wing Building, 1951-1953. (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Letter to the Congregation, 1954-1964. (Box 17, Folder 7)
- The Lion's Tale, 1996. (Box 17, Folder 8)
- The Lion's Tale, 1997. (Box 17, Folder 9)
- The Lion's Tale, 1998-1999. (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Long Range Planning Committee, 1985-1986. (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Long Range Planning Committee Report, not dated. (Box 17, Folder 12)
- "The Making of a Minister: The Reverend Boyd R. Howarth", 1969. (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Marriage Register, 1930-1979. (Box 46)
  Also available on microfilm Misc. Reel 5857.
- Membership and Visitation Committee, 1974-1976. (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Membership List, 1878. (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Membership Register, 1916. (Box 46)
- Memorial -- F. J. Warnecke, 1977-1979. (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Memorials, 1953-1957. (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Memorials Committee, 1965-1976. (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Memorial Fund, 1967-1978. (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Memorial Fund Letters, 1956-1963. (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Memorial Fund Letters, 1964-1966. (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Memorial Service -- The Reverend Boyd Roberts Howarth, 1989. (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Memorial Service -- Petronius Jones, 1992. (Box 18, Folder 6)
- "The Messenger", 1942. (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services, 1962-1964. (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services, 1964-1965. (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services, 1964-1965. (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services, 1965-1966. (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services, 1964-1967. (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services 1968, 1967-1968. (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services 1969, 1968-1969. (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services 1970, 1967-1970. (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services 1972, 1970-1972. (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services 1973, 1973-1974. (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services 1974, 1973-1974. (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services 1974, 1971-1979. (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services 1975, 1974-1975. (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services 1976, 1975-1976. (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Noon-Day Lenten Services: Publicity Committee, 1964-1972. (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Organ and Music Committee, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Organ Fund, 1960-1969. (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Organ Information -- Aeolian -- Skinner Organ Company, 1964. (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Organ Information -- Allen Organs, not dated. (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Organ Information -- Angell Pipe Organs, Inc., 1964. (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Organ Information -- Austin Organs, Inc., 1964. (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Organ Information -- Compton-America Company, 1960-1961. (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Organ Information -- Hillgreen, Lane and Company, 1964-1965. (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Organ Information -- M.P. Moller, Inc., 1964. (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Organ Information -- Reuter Organ Company, 1964. (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Organ Information -- Strawbridge and Clothier, 1960. (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Organ Recital by Ralph Kinder, 1925. (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Organization of the Episcopal Church, not dated. (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Outreach Committee, 1989-1995. (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Outreach Committee -- Adult Development Center, 1993-1995. (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Outreach Committee -- Anglican Frontier Missions, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Outreach Committee -- Annual Report, 1992-1993. (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Outreach Committee -- Bloomfield, 1991. (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Outreach Committee -- Budget, 1991-1993. (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Outreach Committee -- William Byrd Community House, 1994. (Box 20, Folder 14)
- Outreach Committee -- Canterbury Bookshop, 1993-1994. (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Outreach Committee -- CARITAS, 1993-1995. (Box 20, Folder 16)
- Outreach Committee -- Court Appointed Special Advocates, 1993-1995. (Box 20, Folder 17)
- Outreach Committee -- Daily Planet, 1993-1995. (Box 20, Folder 18)
- Outreach Committee -- Freedom House, 1991-1995. (Box 20, Folder 19)
- Outreach Committee -- Ecumenical Resource Center of Richmond, 1993. (Box 20, Folder 20)
- Outreach Committee -- Emergency Shelter, 1993-1995. (Box 20, Folder 21)
- Outreach Committee -- Goochland Prison Ministry, 1993-1995. (Box 20, Folder 22)
- Outreach Committee -- GRECoM, 1993. (Box 20, Folder 23)
- Outreach Committee -- Grove House, 1993-1995. (Box 20, Folder 24)
- Outreach Committee -- Habitat for Humanity, 1993. (Box 20, Folder 25)
- Outreach Committee -- Metropolitan Area Resource Clearing House, 1993-1994. (Box 20, Folder 26)
- Outreach Committee -- Migrant Ministry, 1993. (Box 20, Folder 27)
- Outreach Committee -- New Programs, 1992-1994. (Box 20, Folder 28)
- Outreach Committee -- Presiding Bishop's Fund for World Relief, 1992. (Box 20, Folder 29)
- Outreach Committee -- RCAP Food Club, 1992. (Box 20, Folder 30)
- Outreach Committee -- Region X, not dated. (Box 20, Folder 31)
- Outreach Committee -- Richmond Aftercare, 1993-1994. (Box 20, Folder 32)
- Outreach Committee -- Richmond AIDS Ministry, 1992-1995. (Box 20, Folder 33)
- Outreach Committee -- Richmond Chaplaincy Service, 1992-1994. (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Outreach Committee -- Richmond Community Senior Center, 1993. (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Outreach Committee -- Sewanee University, 1993-1994. (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Outreach Committee -- Shepherd's Center, 1993-1994. (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Outreach Committee -- St. James Church, 1994-1995. (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Outreach Committee -- St. Paul's College, 1993-1994. (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Outreach Committee -- Virginia Council of Churches, 1994. (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Outreach Committee -- Virginia's Table, 1993-1995. (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Outreach Committee -- Westminster-Canterbury, 1993-1994. (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Outreach Committee -- YWCA Women's Crisis Center, 1993-1994. (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Parish Meeting Agenda -- Possible Sale of 506 North Boulevard Property, 1981. (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Parish Profile, 1968. (Box 21, Folder 12)
- Parish Profile, 1987. (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Parish Profile, 1996. (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Parish Register, 1866-1886. (Box 42)
- Parish Register, 2 July 1893-17 July 1905. (Box 45)
- Parish Register, 7 May 1905-18 October 1918. (Box 45)
- Parish Register, 1919-1930. (Box 45)
- Parishioner's Card File, not dated. (Box 39)
- Parishioner's Card File, not dated. (Box 40)
- Parishioner's Card File, not dated. (Box 41)
- Parochial Report, 1930-1964. (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Parochial Report, 1959-1972. (Box 21, Folder 16)
- Parochial Report, 1971. (Box 21, Folder 17)
- Parochial Report, 1972. (Box 21, Folder 18)
- Parochial Report, 1973. (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Parochial Report, 1975. (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Parochial Reports, 1970-1975. (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Partner Parish -- Philippines, 1965-1970. (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Passion Week 1977, 1975-1978. (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Passion Week Services 1978, 1977-1979. (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Passion Week Services 1979, 1976-1979. (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Personal Prayer Book, not dated. (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Personnel, 1976-1977. (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Photographs of Rev. Frederick Warnecke, ca. 1950-1952. (Box 22, Folder 9a)
- Pictorial Directory, 1978. (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Planning Committee, 1969-1976. (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Planning Committee, 1977-1978. (Box 22, Folder 12)
- Planning Committee, 1969-1979. (Box 22, Folder 13)
- Pledge Re-enlistment Card, 1935. (Box 22, Folder 14)
- Printing Blocks, not dated. (Box 52)
- Poem in Memory of Virginia Leisfeld, not dated. (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Postcard -- St. Mark's, First and Clay Street, ca. 1905-1909. (Box 22, Folder 16)
- Prologue to the First Record Book of St. Mark's, not dated. (Box 22, Folder 17)
- Property -- Air Conditioning System, 1982-1983. (Box 22, Folder 18)
- Property -- Alarm System, 1980-1983. (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Property -- Alterations and Southern Wing Addition, not dated. (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Property -- Bell Tower, 1981. (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Property -- Brass Railing, 1950. (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Property -- Heating, 1974-1983. (Box 23, Folder 5)